Amy Nicholson

I am an experienced Technical Product Manager with 9 years experience in developing digital products in an Agile environment. With a foundation as an Android software engineer, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and product management skills to deliver exceptional digital solutions.

Experience

Product Analyst AND Digital Sep 2021 - Present

Club Almeida

The Cabinet Office

- Phase 1: Lead User Researcher for the award-winning Find a Grant Service, which involved developing the research strategy, recruitment and running of user research sessions to determine their needs and pain points and then usability testing potential designs
- Phase 2: Product Manager for Find a Grant, built in line with the Government Design System (GDS) my role included defining the roadmap, release management, leading the team, scrum master tasks, and stakeholder management at deputy director level
- As of October 2024, Find A Grant has more than 324k users and has been used to advertise £19.5 billion worth of grants
- I have experience across all phases of government service development Discovery, Alpha, Beta, including taking part in the GDS assessment process
- Developed prototypes using the GDS prototyping toolkit and tested them with users

Scottish Water

- User research and analysis for a 4-week Discovery to understand the business and identify Gen AI use cases
- Analysed these opportunities using affinity mapping, process mapping, and user journey mapping. The analysis then fed into a prioritisation model which took into consideration the objectives of the business
- Led the team to develop the highest scoring use case using AI to read complex design drawings and convert them to JSON. This was then used to run calculations that were previously done manually. Cutting the time from 5-7 hours by a human to 10 mins with more accurate results.

Simon Community Scotland

- Product Owner for the award-winning By My Side app for homelessness charity Simon Community Scotland
- I was responsible for creating and prioritising the backlog, communicating with stakeholders, and ensuring the team was aligned with the product vision
- This app provides resources on harm reduction, domestic violence and mental health, since its release in May 2022 it has saved lives

Software Engineering Team Lead

BBC

Oct 2020 - Sep 2021

iPlayer and Sounds

- Set up, line-managed, and led a team of 4 mobile developers across Android and iOS
- Collaborated with product managers to define the roadmap and prioritise the backlog
- Delivered push notification functionality, a faster login experience, and accessibility improvements

Android Developer BT Sep 2015 - Oct 2020

Mobile Apps

- Developed and maintained mobile applications including My BT, BT Business, Plusnet Mobile, and BT WiFi
- Releasing, managing, and monitoring performance of mobile apps via the Google Play Store

Skills

- Stakeholder managementProduct roadmapping
- Leading cross functional teams
- Business analysis
- Release management

• Product management

Prototyping

- User research & usability testing
- Public Sector GDS
- Mobile app development

Tools

JiraMiro / Mural

● Confluence ● Figma

GDS prototyping toolkit
Azure DevOps

Education and Certifications

B.Sc. Computing (Web Systems Development), Glasgow Caledonian University.
Professional Scrum Product Owner
Professional Scrum Master